Chance Payne

🗣 Sparks, Nevada, United States 🕿 cmpayne5@gmail.com 🛮 (916) 496-4863 🔚 in/chance-payne/

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with knowledge of a wide range of platforms, languages, and technologies. Constantly learning new technologies and will do what it takes to get the job done. Currently specializing in Android Development with past professional experience in Full Stack Web Development and User Experience Design. Quick learner, picking up skills in iOS development and React.

SKILLS

Android Development: Kotlin, Java, Compose, Android Views, Dagger, RX Java

Web Development: Javascript, HTML, Node.js, Angular, Java (Spring), Kotlin (yay cross compilation!)

EXPERIENCE

Senior Android Engineer

Empower

Remote, February 2023 - Present

- · Redesigned feature gating system to facilitate implementation and extendibility. Removed 2,000+ lines of duplicate and unnecessary code.
- · Drove the design of an updated marketing system to improve how we attributed users to campaigns and reported that information to Meta.
- · Developed feature to **drive conversion** for returning users, presenting custom experiences based on recent financial transactions. · Continued the development of the above feature to rethink and redesign entire **returning user experience**
- · Developed multiple components from design requirements in Figma and built into the design system library

Android Engineer

Wealthfront

Remote, January 2020 - December 2022

- · Built and launched an MVP referral program that increased new client accuisition by 20% with a low CAC and 4 month paypack period
- · Worked with Growth and Investing teams to create a new onboarding system which increased adoption of personalized investing by 84%
- · Led the creation of a feature which informed users about potential interest gains with new product, initial data showed that **cross product** adoption increased by 34%

Lead Android Instructor

Bloomtech (formerly Lambda School)

Remote, June 2018 - November 2019

- · Independently designed and built a 4 month Android Instruction program and facilitated it for 40 aspiring developers
- · Designed and wrote over **100 apps** for demo projects and evaluation challenges
- · Coordinated student competence evaluations through 3rd party with positive feedback, showing a high pass rate
- · Onboarded and trained additional instructors and curriculum developers to convert material from Java to Kotlin

Software Engineer

VPI Technology Group

Draper, UT, June 2014 - June 2018

- · Developed multiple **Android** apps to communicate and control external devices over **Bluetooth**
- · Updated and maintain Android apps to control hardware devices over Wi-Fi and USB serial interfaces
- · Created C#, Node.js, and Python applications to control devices over different types of hardware interfaces
- · Designed **User Interfaces** for various projects

Owner/Operator

Business Printing Solutions

Folsom, CA, November 2010 - November 2012

- · Worked closely with clients to **design** a product to meet their specific needs
- · Designed and print marketing and internal documents using Adobe Creative Suite

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Utah Valley University

Orem, UT, January 2014 - May 2017

PROJECTS

Radiological Detection System · User Interface

Designed and built UI and assets for Multimillion-Dollar Radiation Detection System for the US Armed Forces

Smart Sprinkler System · Node.js, Angular, SQL

Built a server to connect to test devices being manufactured, allow for remote monitoring, and store test results for analysis

Wireless Projector App · Android, Java, iOS

Took over an app that connects to a web server running on mini projector, improved the user interface and experience.

Bluetooth Android Apps · Android, Bluetooth, Java

Worked on apps to interact with devices over bluetooth including an Alarm Clock, Power Tools, a Smart Battery, and a Smart Lock